<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>missmorenakos</title>
    <link>https://missmorenakos.com/general/</link>
    <description>Recent content on missmorenakos</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 17:13:11 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://missmorenakos.com/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Being moral, free and reasonable at the same time</title>
      <link>https://missmorenakos.com/general/kantsphilosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 17:13:11 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://missmorenakos.com/general/kantsphilosophy/</guid>
      <description>Do you ask yourself things like am I a good person? When are we free as human beings? Which is a moral worthy action? Or are there specific moral lows that can apply to everybody? So did Immanuel Kant. And he gave us some good answers.
If you studied religion, you concluded that it attempted, among other things, to help us follow moral lows. Kant tried to replace religious authority with the authority of reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I write my blog</title>
      <link>https://missmorenakos.com/general/markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 17:13:11 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://missmorenakos.com/general/markdown/</guid>
      <description>I am a beginner blogger and I want to share some things I learned this week. I built my blog with Hugo. To be honest I didn’t do this all by myself. Hugo, as its site says, “is one of the most popular open-source static site generators”. Although, popular doesn’t mean it’s for everyone. You must be a little tech-savvy.
So if you pick Hugo you have to write your posts in Markdown language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Καραντίνα και χαρακτηριστικά προσωπικότητας</title>
      <link>https://missmorenakos.com/general/personalitytraits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 17:13:11 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://missmorenakos.com/general/personalitytraits/</guid>
      <description>Πώς βιώνεις τη καραντίνα; Τι ρόλο παίζει η προσωπικότητα σου; Υπάρχουν προσωπικότητες που ανταποκρίνονται καλύτερα στην καραντίνα;
Η ανθρώπινη προσωπικότητα είναι μοναδική και πολύπλευρη με χαρακτηριστικά πρότυπα σκέψης, συναισθήματος και συμπεριφοράς. Είναι ενας συνδυασμός ενδογγενών και περιβαλλοντικών παραγόντων, καθώς και εμπειριών. Η προσωπικότητα κάποιου μπορεί να αλλάξει, αλλά τα βασικά χαρακτηριστικά του παραμένουν σταθερά στη διάρκεια της ζωής του.
Οι ψυχολόγοι έχουν καταλήξει σε ένα μοντέλο ταξινόμησης των προσωπικοτήτων, το λεγόμενο “Big 5”.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>